（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
500年の争乱… 春秋戦国時代
500 years of war, the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period.
争いの年月(としつき)は 100を超えた国々を
７つに淘汰(とうた)した
In the many years of war, over one hundred states were reduced to only seven.
世にいう戦国七雄である
The world calls them the Seven Warring States.
あまりに長い動乱に―
Among the never-ending strife, the people have lost hope for a return to peaceful times.
もはや 平穏の時は返らぬと
人々は絶望した
だが 紀元前246年
But, in the year 246 BCE,
秦(しん)の国に 大いなる運命を
背負った若き王が即位した
in the State of Qin, a young king bearing a great destiny has taken the throne.
King of Qin Ying Zheng
第31代秦王 嬴政(えいせい)
The 31st King of Qin, Ying Zheng.
のちの〝始皇帝〞である
Later known as Qin Shi Huang.
( Flag - Qin )
嬴政の出現により―
Though just a little, with the appearance of Ying Zheng,
ごく僅かであるが
未来を開く風が吹き始めていた
winds of a new future began to blow.
信(しん)は
その風に乗っていた
Xin was riding on that wind.
Xin
（信）ヘヘッ…
すげえや こりゃ！
This is awesome.
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
Timing
Seboo
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
Typesetting
rtrs
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I knew at the start that there's no end.
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
First Campaign
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）今 秦の国と魏(ぎ)の国境の地
滎陽(けいよう)を巡る争いは激化していた
Now strife has intensified on the border between the State of Qin and the State of Wei, a place called Rongyang.
黄河(こうが)沿いにある滎陽は
魏の玄関口であり
Built along the side of the Huang He River, Rongyang is the entrance to the State of Wei.
両国にとって
最重要拠点のひとつである
A place of utmost importance for both states.
Rongyang
Huang He
(Yellow River)
Wei
Qin
Mount Song
Jing
Shanyang Castle
Xi Castle
Fan
Wei is gathering three armies from behind.
魏は
後方より３軍を集結
秦国も 各地域の軍を
結集しながら
The State of Qin is concentrating its armies from all regions to go after Rongyang.
滎陽を目指す
These armies are both on the scale of over 150,000.
150,000
規模は 両軍ともに15万強
This year's biggest battle has become Xin's first campaign.
この年最大の戦が
信の初陣となった
ついに初陣か…
これが天下の大将軍への第１歩だ
Finally, my first campaign.
This is my first step to being greatest general under the heavens.
俺は やるぜ 漂(ひょう)！
I'm gonna do it, Piao!
ウウッ… いってえ…
Ow...
（尾平(びへい)）
相変わらず うるせえヤツだ
You're as noisy as ever.
ウウッ… 何しやがる！
What the hell?!
Haven't seen you in a while, Xin.
Wei Dao                                     Wei Ping
（尾到(びとう)）
久しぶりだな 信
Oh! Wei Dao! Wei Ping!
（信）
オオッ… 尾平 尾到！
オオッ！ チンピラ兄弟
お前らも来てたのかよ！
If it ain't the hoodlum brothers!
You guys came, too?!
（尾平）“チンピラ”って言うな
このバカガキ！
Don't call us hoodlums, you stupid brat!
村のみんなは元気か？
Is everyone in the village doing okay?
ああ 里典(りてん)の嫌みも相変わらずだ
Yeah. Li Dian is as much a jackass as always.
（尾平）しっかし お前も
村にいるころと 全然 変わらねえな
But you're still the same from when you lived in the village.
いまだに“天下の大将軍”とか
バカみたいなこと言ってやがるし
You're still saying that stupid stuff about "greatest general under the heavens", eh?
ンッ！ バカじゃねえよ
絶対になるんだよ 俺は！
It ain't stupid!
I'm seriously gonna become it!
（尾平）それが“バカ”って
言ってんだよ このバカガキ！
I'm saying that is stupid, you stupid brat.
State of Qin Xianyang
（貂(てん)）俺の名は…
My name is...
He Liao Diao!
河了貂(かりょうてん)なり！
（番兵）通ってよし！
You may pass!
Do I have to do this every time?
毎回やんのか？ これ
（政）そうか 信の初陣か…
I see. Xin's first campaign, is it?
（貂）ああ
気合い入りまくってたぞ
He Liao Diao
Yeah. He's really fired up about it.
まあ いきなり
大手柄なんて
Not that getting some big achievements right off the bat will be that easy.
うまく
いくはずないけどさ
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）ここでしたか…
（貂）うん？
Is this where you were?
Changwenjun
*Closest aide to Ying Zheng
（昌文君）先ほど
第４軍が出陣しました
The 4th army just departed a short while ago.
（政）魏の国か…
The State of Wei...
代々 秦国の東への道を
閉ざしてきた国
The kingdom that has blocked the State of Qin's path eastward for generations.
（昌文君）四方に敵国を構え
数百年 戦に明け暮れているせいで
Pay mind that there are enemy states in every direction.
After nothing but war for hundreds of years,
全軍が戦いに慣れています
all of the armies are experienced in battle.
中でも 戦車隊は
中華で一二を争う屈強さです
Among them are mighty chariot corps in competition to be the strongest in all of China.
せ… 戦車隊…
（政）あの国は手ごわいぞ
Ch-Chariot corps...?
That kingdom is strong.
I-I'm sure Xin'll be all right.
だ… 大丈夫だよな？ 信
It will be a brutal battle...
（昌文君）
激しい戦になるだろう
命を
落とさなければよいが…
Hopefully he isn't killed, but...
不吉なこと言うな！
Don't say something unlucky like that!
あいつが
そう簡単に死ぬわけないだろう！
You can't kill that guy so easily!
あいつらしい…
（貂）うん？
It suits him.
（政）厳しい戦いになりそうだ
It looks to be... a relentless fight.
What's everyone gathering together for?
みんな集まって 何してんだ？
（百人将）これより 伍(ご)を作る！
伍長 集まれ！
We are now forming Wu!
Wuchangs, gather!
うん？ 伍？
（尾平･尾到）えっ？
Wu?
Wu (Five/Fireteam)
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）当時 歩兵は―
At this time, foot soldiers had institutionalized moving in 5-man teams called "Wu".
“伍”と称される５人１組での
行動が制度化されていた
Wu (Five/Fireteam)
Wuchang (Corporal)
伍のリーダーは伍長と呼ばれ
The leaders of a Wu are called Wuchangs.
A Wu is a standard unit in the Qin infantry.
秦の歩兵軍にあっては
伍が基本単位であり
この５人組は運命共同体である
These groups of five share a single fate.
（歩兵Ａ）田有(でんゆう) 俺の伍に入れ！
Tian You! Join my Wu!
（歩兵Ｂ）バカ野郎！
前も お前んとこだったんだろうが
You idiot! He was with yours before, wasn't he?!
He's joining my Wu this time!
（歩兵Ｂ）今度は俺の伍だ
Tian You, wait!
（歩兵Ａ）田有 待ってくれ！
It's Zhong Tie!
（歩兵Ｃ）
中鉄(ちゅうてつ)だ！ 殺し屋の中鉄がいるぞ！
Zhong Tie the assassin!
（歩兵Ｄ）
よっしゃ 俺の伍に入ってくれ！
All right! Join my Wu!
特別待遇してやるぞ
I'll give you special treatment!
ウオ～ッ！ なるほど
強そうなヤツから売れていくんだな
I get it!
So they start by going for the strong-looking guys!
Aw dammit! Nobody knows about me yet, I guess!
ちっくしょう！ 俺のことは
みんな まだ知らねえからな
Okay!
よし！
（尾平･尾到）えっ？
Listen up everyone!
みんな 聞きやがれ！
城戸村(じょうとむら)の信とは 俺のことだ！
I'm Xin of Chenghu Village!
体は ちっせえが
誰よりも強(つえ)えぞ こら！
I may be small,
but I'm stronger than anybody, dammit!
ふざけんな てめえら！
天下の大将軍になる この俺を！
Quit screwin' around, you bastards!
Don't you know I'm gonna be greatest general under the heavens...
おい やめろ 見苦しい！
（信）離せ てめえ！ やるぞ こら
Hey, stop! It's painful to watch!
Let me go, jackass!
I'll kill you, dammit!
（強面(こわもて)Ａ）おい
（信たち）えっ？
Hey!
You guys're new, right?
（強面Ａ）お前ら 新顔だな
お前 いい体してんじゃねえか
You're pretty built, ain'cha?
（強面Ｂ）こっちが兄貴か？
This one's the big brother?
んじゃ 兄弟で入れてやるよ
これで５人だ
Then we'll take both brothers.
That makes five.
あの ちっこいのは弟か？
Is that shrimp your little brother?
兄弟 別れるのがイヤだったら
ほかを当たるぞ
If you don't wanna split your family up, we'll try somebody else.
（尾平）
いや あいつは同郷なだけッス
Nah, that guy just lives in the same village as us.
関係ないッス
（強面Ａ）そうか
We barely even know him.
Really?
ンンッ！ くっだらねえ
Screw this! Seriously!
ああ くっだらねえ！
大の男が５人も集まって
気色悪いんだよ バ～カ！
Bringing five big guys together is creepy, you morons!
俺は１人で てめえら５人分
戦うっつうんだよ バ～カ！
I'll take the five of you on myself, idiots!
よう お前も売れ残りか？
So you're a leftover, too, huh?
ハハハッ… 俺より ちっせえな
そりゃダメだ
You're even smaller than me!
That ain't good!
まあ 座れよ
残り物(もん)同士 仲良くしようぜ
Well, sit down.
Us leftovers gotta stick together.
Hey, I went out of my way to talk to you, don't ignore me.
おい せっかく
話しかけてやってんのに―
無視すんなよ！ ンンッ！
おい てめえ 座れっつってんだよ！
聞いてんのか？
Hey, you! I said sit down! Can't ya hear me?!
We're back.
（尾平）ただいま
（信）ああ？ 何だよ？ お前ら
Huh?! What's with you guys?!
（尾到）ほかに強そうなのが
いたから 捨てられた
There were other guys they thought looked stronger, so they got rid of us.
（歩兵Ｅ）
あれ？ 澤(たく)伍長 また１人だぜ
Oh? Ze Wuchang is alone again.
Wuchang   Ze Gui
（歩兵Ｆ）
しょうがねえよな
Ah, well.
誰も
あんな頼りない伍長に
Nobody'd wanna put their lives in the hand of a Wuchang that unreliable.
命 預けたくねえもんな
（澤圭(たくけい)）ハァ…
（歩兵）
ハハハハッ… よう！ 澤１人長
Hey, lone captain Ze!
（澤圭）ああ またしても
誰も組んでくれなかった
Yeah, looks like nobody joined with me again.
今回の売れ残りは…
And the leftovers this time...
アア… ２人は まだ子供じゃないか
Ah, two of them are still kids, ain't they?
今回は無事に帰れるのかな？
I wonder if we'll make it back okay this time.
Cut it out already!
いいかげんにしやがれ！
（信）うっせえな…
Shut up!
うっせえ！ やるぞ この野郎！
I'll beat the crap outta you!
Um...
（澤圭）あの…
（信たち）うん？
どうも 伍長の澤圭です
皆さん よろしく
Hello. I'm Wuchang Ze Gui.
Nice to meet you, everyone.
Well, fine.
まあ いいけどよ
おい お前 名前は？
Hey, you, what's your name?
てめえ！ いいかげんに…
Bastard! Would you cut out the...
Qiang Lei
Qiang Lei.
（羌瘣(きょうかい)）羌瘣
My dislikes are talking.
嫌いなことは
しゃべること　以上
And that is all.
（澤圭）と… とにかく この５人が
お互い 命を預け合う仲間です
A-Anyhow, us five are comrades that will be entrusting each other with our lives.
助け合って 頑張っていきましょう
（信）フン！
（信）ンン～ッ！
こりゃ絶好の行軍日和だな
So let's do our best to help each other.
This sure is great weather for a march!
これで カンに障るクソガキが
いなければ 最高なのによ！
こいつ
なんで こんなに緊張感ねえんだ？
If only we didn't have an irritating shitty brat here, this would be the tops!
初陣ばっかりの伍で
こっちは不安いっぱいなのに…
Why's this guy so relaxed?
For the Wu of our first campaign, we've got a lot to be worried about.
ハァ…
（信）うん？ どうした？ お前
What's up?
秦国の旗だ！
That's the State of Qin's flag!
（信）俺たちのほかにも
歩兵軍がいたのか！
So there's an infantry besides us?!
あれが第４軍の本隊です
That's the main unit of the 4th army.
今から
我々は あそこに吸収されます
We're going to be absorbed by it.
第４軍？
4th army?
…てことは ほかに あと３つも
あんな でかい軍があるのか？
Does that mean there are three other armies that gigantic?
There are five.
（澤圭）
５つです 全部で６軍ですよ
There are six armies in total.
（尾到）ろ… ６軍？
S-Six?!
す… すっげえ！
A-Awesome!
This is so awesome!
すげえよ！ すげえ！
So awesome...
So damn awesome!
すっげえー！
Forward!
進めー！ 進軍しろ！
Forward march!
（歩兵Ｇ）何だ？ あいつ
（歩兵Ｈ）うぜえぞ ガキ！
What's with that guy?
Pipe down, brat!
（澤圭）
信君って どんな子なんですか？
What sort of boy is young Xin?
（尾平）ああ
見たまんまのバカです なっ？
As you can see, he's an idiot.
うん？ どうした？
What's up?
Nothing... I just imagined something and it gave me a bad feeling.
いや ちょっと想像したら
気持ち悪くなって…
Imagined? What?
（尾平）想像？ 何を？
こんだけの人数が殺し合いをしたら
どんな光景になるのかなって…
With this many people killing each other,
what's that scene gonna look like?
く… くだらねえこと想像すんなよ
（尾到）で… でも…
Don't go imagining worthless crap like that!
B-But...
（伝令Ａ）
全軍 整列！ 全軍 整列だ！
All units, line up! All units, line up!
（信）えっ？ 何だ？
What?
千人将の騎馬隊が通るぞ
全軍 整列だ！
The Thousand-Man General Qima unit is coming through!
All units, line up!
千人将？
Thousand-Man General?
（信）前行こうぜ 前！
Let's head to the front!
あっ こら 待て 信！
（信）ちょっと ごめんよ
Hey, hold on, Xin!
S'cuse me.
All right! We're right up front!
よっしゃ 最前列！
Please try not to put the line in disorder.
くれぐれも
列を乱さないでくださいね
Under martial law, Qin's Qima unit is quite harsh.
秦国の騎馬隊は軍律に厳しく
千人将は
気性の激しい方が多いですから
And their Thousand-Man General is often quite violent, so...
とにかく 列を乱さないように
お願いしますよ
Anyhow, please, do not upset the line.
ウ～ッ！ かっけえ！
（尾平）動くな バカ
Cool!
Don't move, idiot!
It's a line of four chariots.
４連戦車です　千人将が来ますよ
A Thousand-Man General is coming.
えっ？ どれどれ？
（尾平）こら！
Which one is he?!
Hey!
うわぁ…
Xin!
信！
（尾到）死んだ…
He's dead!
Halt!
（千人将）止まれ！
（沛浪(はいろう)）
あいつ とんでもねえアホだな
That guy's incredibly stupid.
（脇次(きょうじ)）フフフッ…
見てなよ　首が すっ飛ぶぜ
Just watch. His head's gonna go flying.
I thought you'd be here.
（千人将）やはり いたか
よう 壁(へき) 久しぶり！
Hey, Bi!
It's been a while!
You never change, Xin.
（壁）相変わらずだな 信
元気そうで 何よりだ
But I'm glad you're doing well!
Who the hell is that brat?!
（山和(さんか)）あのガキ 一体 何者だ？
千人将相手に
やけに なれなれしかったな
He's spoke to a Thousand-Man General
and sounded pretty familiar with him.
ケッ… どうせ
昔 下僕として仕えてたんだろう
I guess he must've worked for him before as a servant.
But he was using casual speech!
（脇次）でも タメ口だったぞ
どういうこった？
What's with that?
信君って どんな子なんですか？
What sort of boy is young Xin?
As you can see, he's an idiot...
見たまんまのバカ
…のはずなんスが
I think...
Thousand-Man General  Bi
*One of Ying Zheng's Close Aides
また少し たくましく
なったようだな
Looks like you've bulked up some more.
壁のあんちゃんこそ 見違えたぜ
千人将って すげえじゃんか！
And I barely recognized you, Brother Bi!
Thousand-Man General? That's awesome!
これで
また一緒に戦えるってわけだな
Now we can fight together again, huh?!
（壁）それは まだ分からん
I don't know that yet.
第４軍は３万人
The 4th army has 30,000 men.
私は その中の1,000人を
率いる千人将のひとりだ
I'm leading one of those thousand as a Thousand-Man General.
直属の将になるかは―
Whether or not I become a supervising general will be decided
このあと 我々が向かう丸城(がんじょう)での
軍編成によって決まるのだ
on how the unit formation at the place we're headed to, Wan Castle, works out.
そっか　千人将っつっても
いっぱい いるんだな
I see.
Even though the title is Thousand-Man General, there sure are a lot of 'em.
されど千人将は千人将
これからは敬語を使うように
Be that as it may, a Thousand-Man General is a Thousand-Man General.
Please use polite language from here on out.
You'll set a bad example for the others.
ほかの者に示しがつかぬ
（信）は～い
Fiiine.
By the way, Xin...
それで 信
お前は どんな伍に入ったのだ？
What sort of Wu did you form?
疲れ切った伍長と あとはド素人
A worn out Wuchang and a bunch of newbies.
周りからは
“最弱の伍”って からかわれてる
I'm hearing a lot of people mumbling "weakest Wu" around us.
最弱…
Weakest...?
まあ 伍は ２人 手だれがいれば
安定するといわれているからな
Well, they say that if a Wu has two strong members, then you should be safe.
I wonder if you'll be okay as the only one.
信ならば １人でも大丈夫か
おうよ！
俺が５人分 働けば問題ねえ
Hell yeah I will! I've just gotta do the work of five people!
フッ… よし！
ならば 先に丸城で待っているぞ
Okay. Then I'll be waiting up ahead at Wan Castle.
おう 壁千人将！
Right, Thousand-Man General Bi!
The 4th army is at Wan Castle...?
（澤圭）第４軍は丸城ですか…
マズイことになりましたね
This really isn't good...
丸城の城主 黒剛(こくごう)将軍は
“星眼(せいがん)の黒龍(こくりゅう)”と恐れられ
The lord of Wan Castle, General Hei Gang is feared by many as the Star Eye Black Dragon.
先の戦では 僅か2,000の兵で
３万の敵を撃破した猛将です
He is a monstrous general which, in the last war, led just 2,000 soldiers to attack 30,000 enemy soldiers.
Especially in this war, we're being appointed to the fiercest battlefield..
特に この戦で最激戦地を任され
There's bound to be more blood flowing there than usual...
いつも以上に
血がたぎっておられるはず
…てことは 俺たちは
その将軍の歩兵として戦うのか
So you're saying we're gonna fight as that general's soldiers?
マジかよ やったぜ！ なあ？ 尾到
Seriously?! All right!
Right, Wei Dao?!
えっ？
いや 俺は胃が痛くなってきた…
Uh, my stomach is starting to hurt...
（信）最激戦地ってことは―
Fiercest battlefield?! That means we'll be rolling in achievements!
それだけ
手柄が転がってるってことだ
ク～ッ！ 燃えてきた！
I'm so fired up!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
だが 戦の渦は 信の思惑をのみ込み
But the maelstrom of war drew in Xin's predictions
bringing about further disarray.
更なる混沌(こんとん)を生みだそうとしていた
State of Qin  Wan Castle
そのころ 丸城では…
At that time at Wan Castle...
( Flag - Wei )
What?! Wan Castle fell?!
なに？ 丸城が落ちただと！
How?!
なんでだ？
攻めようとしてる こっちが
なんで逆に城を落とされてんだよ？
I thought we were the ones attacking, how'd we get attacked?!
黒剛将軍は どうした？
すげえ強い将軍なんだろう？
What happened to General Hei Gang?!
He's a crazy strong general, ain't he?!
They said he died in battle.
（澤圭）討ち死にされたそうです
（信）なっ…
Wha-?!
将軍だけではありません
城内の人間は―
And it wasn't just the general.
Down to the elderly, women, and children inside the castle,
老人 女子供に至るまで
皆殺しにされたそうです
everyone was slaughtered.
（尾平）
初めてで分かんねえんスけど…
This is my first time so I didn't know,
戦争って
そこまでやるもんなんスか？
but do wars always go that far?
No. This is the first time I've heard of something like this as well.
（澤圭）
いえ こんなことは 私も初めてです
（信）どこの どいつだ？ そんな
ふざけたマネしやがったのは！
Who the hell would pull terrible shit like that?!
Most likely, it's Wei's General Wu Qing.
恐らく 魏の呉慶(ごけい)将軍
To have defeated General Hei Gang,
黒剛将軍を倒したということは―
he must have extraordinary talent for battle.
尋常ならざる戦の才を
持っていると思われます
That doesn't matter!
（信）関係ねえ！
（尾平･尾到）うん？
どんな将軍だろうが
ぶっ殺すだけだ！
No matter what sorta general he is, we've just gotta kill him!
（尾平）け… けどよ
B-But...
The castle we were supposed to enter, Wan Castle fell, so...
入城するはずだった丸城が
落とされちまって
俺たちは
これから どこに向かうんスか？
Where do we go from here?
（澤圭）亜水(あすい)です
Yashui.
そこで 第１軍 ２軍と合流して
We'll combine with the 1st and 2nd armies there
and attack Rongyang head on.
正面から 滎陽を
攻めることになってしまいました
（尾平）
それって かなりヤバイんじゃ…
That sounds pretty dangerous.
最悪です
It's the worst thing that could happen.
んじゃ
やっぱ 最激戦地に行くんだな！
Then it looks like we are going to the most violent battlefield!
願ったりだ この野郎！
It all worked out, dammit!
（信）
妙に空気がピリピリしてきやがった
The atmosphere has gotten oddly tense...
I see. So this is what it feels like right before a battle.
なるほど
戦が近いってのは こういうことか
（歩兵）
おい てめえ！ 今 足踏んだろう
Hey, you!
You just stepped on my foot, didn't ya?!
（歩兵）ケッ！
よく見りゃ 最弱の伍の連中かよ
Hey, you're those guys from the weakest Wu.
ジャマくせえな
足引っ張る前に とっとと帰れや
You're just in the way. Before you start dragging us down with you, why don't you just go home?
て… てめえ！
（澤圭）あ… あの…
Y-You bastard!
U-Um...
何だ？ てめえら
やんのか？ こら！
What's with you?
You wanna go, dammit?!
な… なに？
Wh-What?
Y-You mustn't!
（澤圭）い… いけませんよ
行軍中の私闘は罪に問われます
Fighting amongst ourselves during a march is considered a crime!
（澤圭）ここは 私に免じて…
Please, out of consideration for me...
くそ！
Dammit!
ただ者(もん)じゃねえとは思ってたが…
I didn't think he was a nobody...
フッ…
野郎 いろいろ隠してやがるな
But that bastard's really hiding a lot...
State of Wei  Rongyang
General Wu Qing, I'm much obliged for the reinforcements!
（隆太(りゅうたい)）
呉慶将軍 援軍 痛み入ります
Now that you're here, General,
将軍に来ていただいたからには―
もはや
この滎陽はビクともいたしませぬ
Rongyang is impenetrable!
（呉慶）援軍ではない
（隆太）はぁ？
We are not reinforcements.
Sir?
I came here to take Rongyang's whole army.
私は 滎陽の全軍をもらいに来た
Whole army?
全軍？ ど… どういうことです？
Wh-What do you mean?
General   Wu Qing
*Wei Army Supreme Commander
薄汚い侵略者が
I will never allow those dirty invaders to set foot in my land of Wei!
我が魏の地を踏むことは
断じて許さぬ
ま… まさか 呉慶将軍…
General Wu Qing, you don't intend to...
State of Qin   Yashui
（赤伝者）急報！ 急報！
Urgent report! Urgent report!
Just now, Wei army forces set out from Rongyang just a short time ago.
（赤伝者）先ほど 魏の軍勢が
滎陽を打って出たとのこと
数は15万　率いるは呉慶
Their number is 150,000.
Leading them is Wu Qing!
Next they're heading straight here, to Yashui!
まっすぐ
ここ 亜水を目指しています
（千人将Ａ）なんだと？ 15万？
（千人将Ｂ）滎陽の守備の全軍だぞ
What?!
150,000?!
That's Rongyang's entire defense!
（千人将Ｃ）呉慶め
丸城の次は亜水を取るというのか！
That damn Wu Qing. After Wan Castle, he intends to take Yashui?!
どういうことだ？
What's going on? The 1st and 2nd armies are already here.
ここには
既に 第１軍 第２軍が入城し
歩兵軍がいなかった丸城とは
ワケが違う
It's completely different from Wan Castle that had no infantry...
何か策でも あるのか？
Does he have some strategy...?
（麃公(ひょうこう)）うろたえるな！
（壁）ハッ…
Do not be perturbed!
Wu Qing has no plans to attack Yashui.
（麃公）
呉慶は ここなど狙っておらぬ
General  Biao Gong
*Qin Army Supreme Commander
He merely wishes to bring the battle to the plains
ヤツは ただ
魏の主力の戦車隊が
生きる平地戦に
where the Wei's mighty chariots will come to life.
持ち込みたいだけじゃ
Shegan Plain, huh?
蛇甘(だかん)平原か… 面白いのぅ
Interesting.
The attack of Rongyang is on hold!
滎陽攻めは中止じゃ！
平地戦に切り替える
We're switching to a battle on the plains!
Yashui
Rongyang
Shegan Plain
滎陽と亜水の中間 蛇甘平原を
決戦の地とする
The battle will take place on the area between Rongyang and Yashui, Shegan Plain!
Take position on the hills as soon as possible!
いち早く丘に布陣すべし
今すぐ たつぞ！
Head out immediately!
（将Ａ）今すぐ？
Immediately?!
But the formation of units haven't finished yet!
（将Ｂ）しかし
軍の編成が まだ終わっていません
しかも 第４軍は いまだ入城すら…
And the 4th army has yet to arrive...
（麃公）そんなものは
蛇甘平原に着いてからでよい
We can just do those things on Shegan Plain!
Have the 4th army head to Shegan Plain directly!
第４軍も直接 蛇甘へ向かわせよ
（壁）素早い対応ではある
He is quite quick to adapt.
平地戦で 見晴らしのいい丘に
布陣したいのも分かる
I can understand the reasons for taking position on the hills which will give a good view of the battle on the plain.
But it's too light...
しかし 軽すぎる
蛇甘平原まで 走れば３日
滎陽からは４日
If we hurry, it will take 3 days to reach Shegan Plain. And 4 days from Rongyang.
すなわち ３～４日後に
魏と ぶつかるということ
Which means we will collide with Wei between 3 and 4 days from now.
だが 兵も軍も準備はできていない
But neither the soldiers nor the armies are prepared.
当然だ　予定では出陣は10日後
It's only natural, the plan was to depart 10 days from now.
しかも 城攻めという予定だった
And the plan had been for it to be an attack on a castle.
Is this general reliable...?
大丈夫なのか？ この将軍は
麃公 一体 どんな将軍なのだ？
Biao Gong...
Just what kind of general is he...?
全軍 出陣じゃ！
All units, depart!
（信）
なんで いきなり駆け足なんだよ？
Why are we running all of a sudden?
I don't know.
（澤圭）分かりません
ただ 目的地が 亜水から
蛇甘平原に変わったようです
But it seems our goal has changed from Yashui to Shegan Plain.
（尾平）ええっ？
ま… また変わったんスか？
It-It changed again?!
What's going on?!
（信）どうなってんだ？
これで２度目だぞ
This is the second time!
Most likely this also has to do with the movements Wei has made...
恐らく 今度も
魏に何か動きがあったのでしょう
いいですか？ 皆さん
心の準備をしておいてください
Understand, everyone? Please prepare your hearts and minds for this...
Even though we were originally going to attack, now we're way behind everyone...
攻めるはずの こちらが
後手後手に回っている
こういうときは 大勢 死にます
In times like this, many people die.
（尾平）し… 信 お前 飛ばすな！
X-Xin! Quit flyin' ahead!
す… 少しは 伍のこと考えろ！
Th-Think about your Wu a little!
（尾到）
いつの間にか 先頭集団にいるし
At some point we ended up in the lead!
飛ばしてねえよ！
I ain't flying!
ちゃんと
お前らに合わせて走ってらぁ
You guys just need to hustle and catch up with me!
（尾平）ご… 伍長 もう５日目だ
W-Wuchang... This is the fifth day already...
もう着いてもいいんじゃねえんスか
蛇甘平原に…
Aren't we almost there? Shegan Plain...
Yes. I think we should be arriving soon.
そうですね そろそろだと思います
The air suddenly changed just now...
今 急に空気が変わった
この先に何かいる
There's something past here...
（尾平）おい 信！ どうした？
Hey, Xin!
What's going on?!
H-Hey you!
（兵士）こ… こら 貴様！
先導車を抜くな！
Don't go in front of the guide chariot!
どんどん熱くなる
It's getting hotter and hotter...
It's getting heavier and heavier...
どんどん重くなる
何だ？ この感じ
ムタともランカイとも違う
What is this feeling?
It's different from with Muta and Lankai...
だが 間違いねえ
But there's no doubt about it...
There's something coming up soon!
すぐ目の前に 何か いやがる
とんでもねえ何かが！
Something huge!
( Flag - Wei )
な… 何だ こりゃ！
Wh-What is this?!
kowaresou na kokoro tsumugu youni
壊れそうな心 紡ぐように
To weave together my breaking heart
yume no kakera mitsume (No more cry)
夢のカケラ見つめ (No more cry）
I gaze at the fragments of a dream (No more crying)
me no mae ni wa tsuki ga utsushidasu
目の前には月が映し出す
The moon I see before my eyes
kono mune no yakusoku
この胸の約束
reflects this promise in my heart
namida ga nokoshita kioku sae mo
涙が残した記憶さえも
I won't turn away from my tearful memories
～♪
waraiatta kako sae furimukanai
笑いあった過去さえ振り向かない
nor the past where we laughed together
Voice of soul
Voice of you
（信）
くそ！ 手の出しようがねえ！
kanashimi nara kitto tsuyosa ni kawaru hazu
悲しみならきっと 強さに変わるはず
Sadness is sure to turn into strength
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）逃げ場なし
命が衝撃の速さで砕かれる
I won't cry
次回“戦車隊の脅威”
I won't fear
I won't stop
takaku tobeba kitto sora no mukou ni todoku
高く翔べばきっと空の向こうに届く
If I jump high enough, I'm sure I'll reach beyond the sky
Voice of mine
Yeah
Voice of soul
Preview
Shit, there's no way in!
There is no running.
Life is broken by the speed of an impact.
The Threat of the Chariot Corps
Next time,
End
The Threat of the Chariot Corps